{"data":[{"question":"We ______ for about an hour when the car suddenly made an awful noise and stopped.","a":"ve been driving","b":"d been driving","c":"were driving","d":"has been driving","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"(Your friend sneezes) \nYou: Bless you! \nYour friend: Thanks. I think I've got a cold. ________ all morning.","a":"I'd been sneezing","b":"I've been sneezing","c":"I was sneezing","d":"I has been sneezing","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \n- Sneezed all morning- got a cold \n- Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"We felt very tired after the meeting yesterday because we ______ for hours.","a":"had been talking","b":"have been talking","c":"were talking","d":"has been talking","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \n- Talked for hours- tired \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"When we arrived to take Joe to the airport, he was still packing his suitcase. He was late because _______ for his passport.","a":"he's been looking for","b":"he was looking for","c":"he'd been looking for","d":"he've been looking for","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \n- Looked for passport- late \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"This morning while ____ my shower, the phone rang. I decided not to answer it and to finish my shower.","a":"I was having","b":"I've been having","c":"I'd been having","d":"I has been having","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past continuous: to indicate that a longer action in the past was interrupted. The interruption is usually a shorter action in the Simple Past \n+ Structure: S + was\/were + V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"Before she died, my grandmother gave me a little china bowl. It ______ to her mother and was very old.","a":"had belonged","b":"has belonged","c":"had been belonging","d":"have been belonging","answer":"1","explain":"\n- The Past Perfect expresses the idea that something occurred before another action in the past \n- Structure: S + has\/ have + PP \n- Belong is a HYPERLINK \"http:\/\/www.englishpage.com\/verbpage\/types.html\"Non-Continuous Verb which cannot be used in any continuous tenses","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"Ben and Tom were very thirsty after their game of tennis. They _______ in the sun for an hour and a half.","a":"ve been playing","b":"were playing","c":"d been playing","d":"has been playing","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \n- Played in the sun- thirsty \n- Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"A: Hi Kate! \nB: Hi Robert! Hi Amy! Sorry I'm a bit late. \nA: That's OK. We ______ long.","a":"weren't waiting","b":"haven't been waiting","c":"hadn't been waiting","d":"hasn't been waiting","answer":"2","explain":"\n- We use the Present Perfect Continuous to show that something started in the past and has continued up until now \n- Structure: Has\/have + been + V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"The pictures I took with Helen's camera were terrible. I _______ her instructions at all.","a":"hadn't been understanding","b":"hadn't understood","c":"wasn't understanding","d":"weren't understanding","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \n- Didn't understand instructions- terrible pictures \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"},{"question":"Tim was very wet when he arrived at the party. ______ in the rain.","a":"He'd been cycling","b":"He's been cycling","c":"He was cycling","d":"He've been cycling","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \n- Cycled in the rain- wet \n- Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"5","type":"1"}]}